[Music]
My name is Aloe Blacc. I'm a singer and songwriter and entertainer.
♪ So when we are many, it's all over ♪
When it became more and more important for artists
to have a presence on the internet,
I quickly...
We developed the skill to build a website and get online, use my knowledge of coding
to make it so that people could...
Learn more about our music.
Every bit of data or information can be stored digitally. Whether it's numbers...
pictures, music, or video, all of it can be represented digitally. That means the
information can be represented by electrical signals that are on or off, or
as one's...
and zeros, so to speak.
But representing information in ones and zeros can take up a lot of space.
For example, if you wanted to store a three-minute song digitally...
it would take up over 30 megabytes of space. A one-hour HD video would take 800 gigabytes.
In the real world, digital information is compressed.
to take up less space. A 30 megabyte song can be compressed down to 3 megabytes.
An hour long video can be compressed from 800 gigabytes down to just 1 gigabyte.
of light. Sometimes compression is lossy, which means that to save some space, some
of the information is thrown away. For example, an image can
be compressed to a lower resolution to lose some detail. Lossy compression is
useful because in many cases the human eye or ear can't even notice the
details that are being lost.
When you compress data without losing any details, that's called lossless compression.
This means the compressed data can be decompressed back into the exact original.
One way of doing lossless compression is to find patterns in the data you're trying to compress.
As an extreme example, imagine a book about dogs with high levels of fat.
hundreds of pages using only one word.
Each page just says dog, dog, dog, dog, dog,
over and over a million times.
Instead of writing it all out,
you could just store the pattern, dog times one million.
Now that's a silly example but let's look at a more real example.
Instead of a book, imagine the lyrics
of a song. If a single word or phrase is repeated a lot, you can store that once and then reuse
it without repeating the data.
with a simple text compression widget.
This widget lets you experiment with compressing text.
You want to represent the original text
with as few bytes as possible.
The widget is a little bit different.
it lets you try compressing different ways and see it as it happens. Let's see how it
works. The widget shows you some text to compress. In this example, lyrics to one of
Alice in the World.
In the dictionary area, you can type patterns you see in the text.
For now, let's just look for words that repeat.
As you type in the dictionary area, a single word is a word.
symbol would be substituted in the main text area. In the example here you can
see each occurrence of the words "I was" has been replaced with a symbol of a sun
and "I"
time has been replaced with an umbrella.
that they could reconstruct the original text.
So the question is, is the total number
of bytes in the compressed text plus the bytes
in the dictionary less than the number of bytes--
in the original text? The answer is yes for our current example, and the widget shows
you how it's calculated. We assume that every character that needs to be sent takes one
bite.
So the display shows the compressed version of the lyrics with the symbols substituted in it has 216 bytes or characters.
It also shows the number of bytes of the lyrics.
in the dictionary as 10. This is to store the words "I was" and "I'm" also the symbols
that represent those patterns. This gives us a total of 200.
We can see that the original text had 240 characters or bytes, so we reduced the bytes
needed to represent the poem by 14 bytes.
or 5.8% not a bad start. Looking for words that repeat is a good start but
you can look for other patterns. Sometimes a repeating pattern
could be a subpart of a word or many words.
Here's where it really gets cool.
You can find patterns that include dictionary symbols
you just made.
For example, we replace words "I was" with a sun symbol, but now you can also see that
a new pattern didn't know sun symbol lost.
You can type this in the dictionary too.
As a side note, to enter the sun symbol you need to copy and paste it, unless your keyboard has a sun on it.
With that little change, we're now up to 26% compression.
Try it yourself and see if you can do better.
song lyric or poem is obvious, but really any form of information can have repetition
or patterns in it. They're just not as obvious.
For example, an outdoor
The door's phono can have a blue sky, and instead of storing every single blue pixel,
that can be compressed.
With the amount of information that's digitized and sent around the internet every day,
there are much fancier ways to compress the data. Data compression is now built
into how every picture, a song, or movie is stored, and almost every webpage you
visit is compressed as it's
sent to your device.
All these compression algorithms have one thing in common.
They all aim to represent the information in the smallest format possible, in a way
that
can be decompressed to reconstruct the original, or at least something close to it.
(chimes)